I'm 150 feet down an illegal mine shaft in Ghana.
أنا على انخفاض 150 قدما في مهواة منجم غير قانوني في غانا.
The air is thick with heat and dust,
الهواء كثيف بالحرارة والغبار،
and it's hard to breathe.
و التنفس صعب.
I can feel the brush of sweaty bodies passing me
أستطيع أن أشعر بالأجساد التي تفوح منها رائحة العرق تمر بجانبي
in the darkness, but I can't see much else.
في الظلمة، لا أستطيع رؤية أكثر من ذلك.
I hear voices talking, but mostly the shaft
أسمع أصواتا تتحدث، لكن أغلبها في المصعد
is this cacophony of men coughing,
أصوات متنافرة لرجال يسعلون,
and stone being broken with primitive tools.
وأصوات أحجار يتم تكسيرها بأدوات بدائية.
Like the others, I wear a flickering, cheap flashlight
كالبقية، كنت أضع مصباحا وامضا رخيصا
tied to my head with this elastic, tattered band,
مربوطا على رأسي بهذا الرباط المطاطي الرث،
and I can barely make out the slick tree limbs
وبالكاد يمكنني رؤية فروع الشجرة الملساء
holding up the walls of the three-foot square hole
ممسكة بجدران حفرة مساحتها ثلاثة أقدام مربعة
dropping hundreds of feet into the earth.
نزولا بمئات الأقدام إلى باطن الأرض.
When my hand slips, I suddenly remember a miner
عندما تنزلق يدي، أتذكر فجأة عامل منجم
I had met days before who had lost his grip
كنت قد قابلته قبل أيام من مجيئي والذي انفلتت يده
and fell countless feet down that shaft.
وسقط مسافة أقدام لا تُعد من المصعد.
As I stand talking to you today,
بينما أقف أتحدث إليكم اليوم،
these men are still deep in that hole,
لا يزال أولئك الرجال في عمق تلك الحفرة،
risking their lives without payment or compensation,
يخاطرون بحياتهم من دون دفع أو تعويض،
and often dying.
و غالباً ما يموتون.
I got to climb out of that hole, and I got to go home,
تمكنت من الخروج من تلك الحفرة، و تمكنت من العودة للمنزل،
but they likely never will, because they're trapped in slavery.
لكنهم على الأرجح لن يتمكنوا من ذلك، لأنهم واقعون تحت وطء العبودية.
For the last 28 years, I've been documenting
على مدى الثمانية والعشرين سنة الماضية، قمت بتوثيق
indigenous cultures in more than 70 countries
ثقافات الشعوب الأصلية في أكثر من 70 بلدا
on six continents, and in 2009 I had the great honor
في ست قارات، وفي عام 2009 نلت شرفاً عظيماً
of being the sole exhibitor at the Vancouver Peace Summit.
كوني العارضة الوحيدة في قمة فانكوفر للسلام.
Amongst all the astonishing people I met there,
من بين كل الأشخاص المذهلين الذين قابلتهم هناك،
I met a supporter of Free the Slaves, an NGO
التقيت بأحد أنصار "حرروا العبيد"، وهي منظمة غير حكومية
dedicated to eradicating modern day slavery.
مكرسة لاستئصال عبودية العصر الحديث.
We started talking about slavery, and really,
بدأنا في الحديث عن العبودية، و بالفعل
I started learning about slavery,
بدأت أتعلم عن العبودية،
for I had certainly known it existed in the world,
مع أني كنت أعرف دون شك أنها توجد في العالم،
but not to such a degree.
لكن ليس لهذه الدرجة.
After we finished talking, I felt so horrible
بعد أن أنهينا حديثنا، كان شعوري فظيعاً
and honestly ashamed at my own lack of knowledge
وبكل صدق شعرت بالخجل لقلة معرفتي
of this atrocity in my own lifetime, and I thought,
بهذا العمل الوحشي في حياتي، وتسائلت
if I don't know, how many other people don't know?
إن لم أكن أعرف، كم عدد الآخرين الذين لا يعرفون؟
It started burning a hole in my stomach, so within weeks,
بدأ يؤذيني هذا الأمر، لذا وخلال أسابيع
I flew down to Los Angeles to meet with the director
سافرت إلى لوس أنجلوس لألتقي بمدير
of Free the Slaves and offer them my help.
منظمة "حرروا العبيد" وأعرض عليهم مساعدتي.
Thus began my journey into modern day slavery.
وهكذا بدأت رحلتي إلى عبودية العصر الحديث.
Oddly, I had been to many of these places before.
الغريب أني قد زرت عددا من تلك الأماكن من قبل.
Some I even considered like my second home.
حتى أني كنت أعتبر بعضها كبلدي الثاني.
But this time, I would see the skeletons hidden in the closet.
لكني هذه المرة، اكتشفت الحقائق المخفية.
A conservative estimate tells us there are more than
يخبرنا تقدير متحفظ أن هناك أكثر من
27 million people enslaved in the world today.
27 مليون شخص مستعبدين في العالم اليوم.
That's double the amount of people taken from Africa
وهذا ضعف عدد الأشخاص الذين تم أخذهم من أفريقيا
during the entire trans-Atlantic slave trade.
خلال فترة تجارة الرقيق عبر المحيط الأطلسي بأكملها.
A hundred and fifty years ago, an agricultural slave
منذ 150 عاما، كان الرقيق العامل في المزارع
cost about three times the annual salary
يكلف ثلاث أضعاف الراتب السنوي
of an American worker.
لعامل أمريكي.
That equates to about $50,000 in today's money.
هذا يساوي تقريباً خمسين ألف دولار بالعملة المستخدمة اليوم.
Yet today, entire families can be enslaved for generations
و اليوم، يمكن لعوائل بأكملها أن تكون مستعبدة لعدة أجيال
over a debt as small as $18.
بسبب دين صغير قيمته 18 دولار.
Astonishingly, slavery generates profits
على نحوٍ مدهش، تولد العبودية أرباح
of more than $13 billion worldwide each year.
تُقدر بأكثر من 13 مليار دولار حول العالم كل عام.
Many have been tricked by false promises
خُدع الكثيرون بالوعود الزائفة
of a good education, a better job, only to find
بالحصول على تعليم جيد، ووظيفة أفضل، فقط ليجدوا
that they're forced to work without pay
أنهم مجبرون على العمل من دون أجر
under the threat of violence, and they cannot walk away.
تحت تهديد العنف، ولا يمكنهم الفرار.
Today's slavery is about commerce,
العبودية الحديثة تتعلق بالتجارة،
so the goods that enslaved people produce have value,
فالسلع التي ينتجها الأشخاص المستعبدون لها قيمة،
but the people producing them are disposable.
أما الأشخاص الذين يُنتجونها فيمكن التخلص منهم.
Slavery exists everywhere, nearly, in the world,
توجد العبودية تقريباً في كل مكان في العالم
and yet it is illegal everywhere in the world.
وهي كذلك غير شرعية في كل مكان في العالم.
In India and Nepal, I was introduced to the brick kilns.
في الهند و النيبال دخلت إلى قمائن الطوب.
This strange and awesome sight was like
هذا المنظر الغريب والمذهل يشبه
walking into ancient Egypt or Dante's Inferno.
أن تمشي في مصر القديمة أو جحيم دانتي.
Enveloped in temperatures of 130 degrees,
مطوقين بدرجة حرارة تبلغ 130 درجة مئوية،
men, women, children, entire families in fact,
الرجال والنساء والأطفال، العوائل بكاملها في الواقع،
were cloaked in a heavy blanket of dust,
كانوا ملتفين بغطاء كثيف من الغبار،
while mechanically stacking bricks on their head,
بينما تتراص قطع الطوب على رؤوسهم بطريقة ميكانيكية،
up to 18 at a time, and carrying them
تصل لثمانية عشرة طوبة في المرة الواحدة، يحملونها
from the scorching kilns to trucks hundreds of yards away.
من الأفران الحارقة للشاحنات التي تبعد مئات من الياردات.
Deadened by monotony and exhaustion,
و هم هامدون من الرتابة والتعب،
they work silently, doing this task over and over
يعملون بصمت، يؤدون مهامهم مراراً و تكراراً
for 16 or 17 hours a day.
لمدة 16 أو 17 ساعة يومياً.
There were no breaks for food, no water breaks,
لم يكن هناك فترات راحة للأكل، ولا لشرب الماء،
and the severe dehydration made urinating
و الجفاف الشديد جعل من التبول
pretty much inconsequential.
أمرا غير منطقي جداً.
So pervasive was the heat and the dust
كانت الحرارة والغبار منتشرة
that my camera became too hot to even touch
لدرجة أن آلة الكاميرا الخاصة بي أصبحت حارة جداً و يتعذر علي مسكها
and ceased working.
فتوقفت عن العمل.
Every 20 minutes, I'd have to run back to our cruiser
كان علي أن أعود إلى سيارتنا كل عشرين دقيقة
to clean out my gear and run it under an air conditioner
لتنظيف معداتي و تشغيلها تحت مكيف الهواء
to revive it, and as I sat there,
كي تستعيد قوتها، وبينما كنت جالسةً هناك
I thought, my camera is getting far better treatment
كنت أفكر بأن آلة التصوير خاصتي تلقى معاملة أفضل بكثير
than these people.
من أولئك الناس.
Back in the kilns, I wanted to cry,
عندما عدت للأفران، كنت أريد أن أبكي،
but the abolitionist next to me quickly grabbed me
لكن المؤيد لإبطال الاستعباد الواقف بجانبي جذبني بسرعة
and he said, "Lisa, don't do that. Just don't do that here."
وقال لي : " ليزا، لا تفعلي ذلك، فقط لا تفعلي ذلك هنا. "
And he very clearly explained to me that emotional displays
وشرح لي بوضوح أن إظهار المشاعر
are very dangerous in a place like this,
يُعد أمراً خطيراً في مكان كهذا،
not just for me, but for them.
ليس خطراً علي فقط، بل عليهم أيضاً.
I couldn't offer them any direct help.
لم أستطع أن أعرض عليهم أي مساعدة مباشرة.
I couldn't give them money, nothing.
لم أستطع أن أعطيهم مالا، أو أي شيء.
I wasn't a citizen of that country.
لم أكن مواطنة في تلك البلاد.
I could get them in a worse situation
يُمكن أن أُعرّضم لوضع أسوأ
than they were already in.
من الوضع الذي يعيشونه الآن.
I'd have to rely on Free the Slaves to work
كان علي أن أعتمد على منظمة " حرروا العبيد " لأعمل
within the system for their liberation,
في إطار منظومة من أجل تحريرهم،
and I trusted that they would.
وكنت على ثقة أنهم سيتمكنون من ذلك.
As for me, I'd have to wait until I got home
بالنسبة لي، كان علي أن أنتظر حتى أعود للمنزل
to really feel my heartbreak.
حتى أشعر حقاً بالحسرة في قلبي.
In the Himalayas, I found children carrying stone
في جبال الهيمالايا، وجدت أطفالاً يحملون الحجارة
for miles down mountainous terrain
لعدة أميال أسفل المناطق الجبلية
to trucks waiting at roads below.
للشاحنات التي تنتظرهم في الطرق بالأسفل.
The big sheets of slate were heavier
الألواح الصخرية الكبيرة كانت أثقل
than the children carrying them,
من الأطفال الذين يحملونها،
and the kids hoisted them from their heads
و يرفعها الأطفال من رؤوسهم
using these handmade harnesses of sticks and rope
باستخدام تلك الحمّالات المصنوعة يدوياً من العصي و الحبال
and torn cloth.
و القماش الممزق.
It's difficult to witness something so overwhelming.
من الصعب أن تشهد شيئاً ساحقاً جداً.
How can we affect something so insidious,
كيف يمكن أن نؤثر في شيء خفي جداً،
yet so pervasive?
ومع ذلك متفشٍ جداً؟
Some don't even know they're enslaved,
بعضهم لا يدري أنهم مُستعبدون،
people working 16, 17 hours a day without any pay,
يعمل الناس لمدة 16 أو 17 ساعة يومياً دون أن يُدفع لهم شيء،
because this has been the case all their lives.
لأن هذا كان حالهم طوال حياتهم.
They have nothing to compare it to.
لا يوجد لديهم ما يُقارنونه به.
When these villagers claimed their freedom,
عندما طالب أولئك القرويين بحريتهم،
the slaveholders burned down all of their houses.
قام من يستعبدونهم بإحراق كل منازلهم.
I mean, these people had nothing,
أعني أن أولئك الناس لا يملكون شيئاً،
and they were so petrified, they wanted to give up,
وكانوا جامدين جداً، و أرادوا أن يستسلموا،
but the woman in the center rallied for them to persevere,
لكن المرأة التي تقف في المنتصف، حثتهم على الاستمرار والمثابرة،
and abolitionists on the ground
و المنادون بإلغاء العبودية المتواجدون
helped them get a quarry lease of their own,
ساعدوهم في الحصول على عقد إيجار لمحجرة خاصة بهم،
so that now they do the same back-breaking work,
وهكذا يمكنهم الآن أن يقوموا بنفس العمل المنهك،
but they do it for themselves, and they get paid for it,
لكنهم يقومون به من أجل أنفسهم، ويتقاضون رواتب عليه،
and they do it in freedom.
ويقومون به في جو من الحرية.
Sex trafficking is what we often think of
الاتجار بالجنس هو ما نفكر فيه غالباً
when we hear the word slavery,
عندما نسمع كلمة عبودية،
and because of this worldwide awareness,
وبسبب هذا الوعي في جميع أنحاء العالم،
I was warned that it would be difficult for me to work safely
فقد تم تحذيري أنه سيكون من الصعب علي أن أعمل بأمان
within this particular industry.
ضمن هذه الصناعة بالتحديد.
In Kathmandu, I was escorted by women who had
في كاتماندو، رافقنني نساء
previously been sex slaves themselves.
كُنّ في السابق من رقيق الجنس.
They ushered me down a narrow set of stairs
قدنني إلى مجموعة ضيقة من السلالم
that led to this dirty, dimly fluorescent lit basement.
التي تؤدي إلى هذا القبو القذر المُضاء بشكل خافت بالمصابيح الفلورية.
This wasn't a brothel, per se.
هذا لم يكن بيت دعارة في حد ذاته.
It was more like a restaurant.
كان يشبه المطعم أكثر.
Cabin restaurants, as they're known in the trade,
مطاعم المقصورة، كما تُعرف في هذه التجارة،
are venues for forced prostitution.
هي أماكن للبغاء القسري.
Each has small, private rooms, where the slaves,
كل مطعم يوجد فيه غرف خاصة صغيرة، حيث النساء
women, along with young girls and boys,
المستعبدات، إلى جانب الفتيات والفتيان
some as young as seven years old,
بعضهم لا يتجاوز سنه السابعة،
are forced to entertain the clients,
مُجبرون على تسلية الزبائن،
encouraging them to buy more food and alcohol.
لحثهم على شراء طعام و شراب أكثر.
Each cubicle is dark and dingy,
كل الحجر مظلمة و حقيرة،
identified with a painted number on the wall,
ومُعرّفة برقم مصبوغ على الجدار،
and partitioned by plywood and a curtain.
و مقسمة بواسطة الخشب الرقائقي و الستائر.
The workers here often endure tragic sexual abuse
وفي الغالب، يعاني العاملون هنا من الاعتداء الجنسي المأساوي
at the hands of their customers.
على أيدي عملائهم.
Standing in the near darkness, I remember feeling
عندما أقف في الظلام القريب، أتذكر الشعور
this quick, hot fear, and in that instant,
بهذا الخوف السريع و اللاذع، وفي تلك اللحظة،
I could only imagine what it must be like
لا يمكنني إلا أن أتخيل ماذا يشبه
to be trapped in that hell.
أن تكون محاصراً في ذلك الجحيم.
I had only one way out: the stairs from where I'd come in.
لم يكن يوجد لي إلا طريق واحد للخروج وهو السلالم التي أتيت منها.
There were no back doors.
لم يكن هناك أبواب خلفية.
There were no windows large enough to climb through.
ولم يكن هناك نوافذ كبيرة بما يكفي للقفز منها.
These people have no escape at all,
لا يوجد مهرب لأولئك الأشخاص على الإطلاق،
and as we take in such a difficult subject,
و بما أننا تناولنا موضوعا صعبا كهذا،
it's important to note that slavery, including sex trafficking,
من المهم أن أنبه إلى أن العبودية، بالإضافة إلى تجارة الرقيق الجنسي،
occurs in our own backyard as well.
تحدث في ساحتنا الخلفية كذلك.
Tens of hundreds of people are enslaved in agriculture,
عشرات المئات من الناس مُستعبَدون في الزراعة،
in restaurants, in domestic servitude,
وفي المطاعم وفي الأعمال المنزلية
and the list can go on.
و القائمة تطول.
Recently, the New York Times reported that
أصدرت صحيفة نيويورك تايمز مؤخراً تقريرا يفيد بأنه
between 100,000 and 300,000 American children
بين 100.000 و 300.000 طفل أمريكي
are sold into sex slavery every year.
يتم بيعهم لعبودية الجنس كل عام.
It's all around us. We just don't see it.
كل ذلك يجري حولنا. نحن فقط لا نراه.
The textile industry is another one we often think of
صناعة الغزل و النسيج صناعة أخرى نفكر بها غالباً
when we hear about slave labor.
عندما نسمع عن عمل الرقيق.
I visited villages in India where entire families were enslaved
زرت قرى في الهند حيث توجد عوائل مُستعبدة بكاملها
in the silk trade.
في تجارة الحرير.
This is a family portrait.
هذه صورة عائلة.
The dyed black hands are the father, while the blue
اليدان المصبوغتان بالأسود هي الأب، بينما الأيدي المصبوغة بالأزرق
and red hands are his sons.
و الأحمر هي الأبناء.
They mix dye in these big barrels,
يقومون بخلط الصبغة في هذه البراميل الكبيرة،
and they submerge the silk into the liquid up to their elbows,
ويُغرقون الحرير في السائل حتى يصل إلى مرافقهم،
but the dye is toxic.
و لكن الصبغة سامة.
My interpreter told me their stories.
أخبرني المترجم المرافق لي عن قصصهم.
"We have no freedom," they said.
وقد قالوا: "لسنا أحرارا".
"We hope still, though, that we could leave this house
"لكن مازلنا نأمل مغادرة هذا المنزل
someday and go someplace else
يوماً ما والذهاب إلى مكان آخر
where we actually get paid for our dyeing."
حيث نتقاضى فيه أجراً على عملنا في الصباغة."
It's estimated that more than 4,000 children
يُقدّر أنه يوجد أكثر من 4.000 طفل
are enslaved on Lake Volta,
مًستعبَد في بحيرة فولتا،
the largest man-made lake in the world.
أكبر بحيرة في العالم صنعها الإنسان.
When we first arrived, I went to have a quick look.
ذهبت لأُلقي نظرة سريعة أول ما وصلنا.
I saw what seemed to be a family fishing on a boat,
رأيت ما يبدو أنها عائلة تصيد السمك على متن قارب،
two older brothers, some younger kids, makes sense right?
أخوين كبيرين وبعض الأطفال الصغار، يبدو منطقياً أليس كذلك؟
Wrong. They were all enslaved.
خطأ. كانوا جميعهم مستعبدين.
Children are taken from their families
تم سلب الأطفال من أهاليهم
and trafficked and vanished,
و تم الإتجار بهم و اختفوا،
and they're forced to work endless hours on these boats
وقد أُجبروا على العمل لساعات طويلة جداً على متن هذه القوراب
on the lake, even though they do not know how to swim.
في البحيرة، على الرغم أنهم لا يجيدون السباحة.
This young child is eight years old.
هذا الطفل يبلغ عمره ثماني سنوات.
He was trembling when our boat approached,
كان يرتجف عندما اقترب قاربنا،
frightened it would run over his tiny canoe.
كان خائفاً أن يدهس قاربه الصغير.
He was petrified he would be knocked in the water.
و تسمّر في مكانه خشية أن يُقذف في الماء.
The skeletal tree limbs submerged in Lake Volta
فروع الأشجار الغاطسة في بحيرة فولتا
often catch the fishing nets, and weary,
غالباً ما تُمسك بشباك الصيد، والأطفال
frightened children are thrown into the water
المنهكون والخائفون يُرمى بهم في الماء
to untether the lines.
لفك الخيوط.
Many of them drown.
و العديد منهم يغرقون.
For as long as he can recall, he's been forced to work
طالما أنه يُمكن أن يعيش، فقد كان يُجبر على العمل
on the lake.
في البحيرة.
Terrified of his master, he will not run away,
لن يهرب خوفاً من سيده.
and since he's been treated with cruelty all his life,
و لأنه كان يُعامل بقسوة طيلة حياته،
he passes that down to the younger slaves
فقد أراد ذلك لعبيده الصغار
that he manages.
الذين يرأسهم.
I met these boys at five in the morning,
قابلت أولئك الصغار في الخامسة صباحاً،
when they were hauling in the last of their nets,
عندما كانوا يسحبون شباكهم،
but they had been working since 1 a.m.
لكنهم كانوا يعملون منذ الواحدة صباحاً
in the cold, windy night.
في الليل البارد والعاصف.
And it's important to note that these nets weigh
ومن المهم أن أنبه إلى أن وزن هذه الشباك
more than a thousand pounds when they're full of fish.
يبلغ أكثر من ألف رطل عندما تكون مليئة بالسمك.
I want to introduce you to Kofi.
أريد أن أعرّفكم بكوفي
Kofi was rescued from a fishing village.
تم إنقاذ كوفي من قرية صيد سمك.
I met him at a shelter where Free the Slaves
التقيت به في ملجأ حيث تقوم فيه منظمة "حرروا العبيد"
rehabilitates victims of slavery.
بتأهيل ضحايا الرِّق.
Here he's seen taking a bath at the well,
شُوهد هنا وهو يستحم عند البئر،
pouring big buckets of water over his head,
يسكب مقدارا كبير من الماء على رأسه،
and the wonderful news is,
و الخبر الرائع هو،
as you and I are sitting here talking today,
بينما نتحدث سوياً اليوم،
Kofi has been reunited with his family,
تم لم شمل كوفي بعائلته،
and what's even better, his family has been given tools
و الأفضل من هذا، تم تزويد عائلته بأدوات
to make a living and to keep their children safe.
لتكسب عيشها منها و لتُبقي الأطفال آمنين.
Kofi is the embodiment of possibility.
كوفي تجسيد للإمكانية.
Who will he become because someone took a stand
كيف صار لأن أحداً اتخذ موقفاً
and made a difference in his life?
وصنع فرقاً في حياته؟
Driving down a road in Ghana
بينما كنا نقود على طريق في غانا
with partners of Free the Slaves,
مع شركاء من منظمة "حرروا العبيد "،
a fellow abolitionist on a moped suddenly sped up
أسرع فجأة زميل داعم بدراجته
to our cruiser and tapped on the window.
إلى مركبتنا وطرق النافذة.
He told us to follow him down a dirt road into the jungle.
طلب منا أن نتبعه إلى طريق ترابي يؤدي للغابة.
At the end of the road, he urged us out of the car,
عند نهاية الطريق، ألح علينا أن نخرج من السيارة،
and told the driver to quickly leave.
و طلب من السائق أن يغادر بسرعة.
Then he pointed toward this barely visible footpath,
ثم أشار إلى هذا الممر الذي يرُى بالكاد.
and said, "This is the path, this is the path. Go."
وقال: "هذا هو الطريق، هذا هو الطريق. اذهبوا."
As we started down the path, we pushed aside the vines
وعندما نزلنا إلى الطريق، قمنا بوضع النبات المعترش جانباً
blocking the way, and after about an hour of walking in,
الذي يسد الطريق، و بعد حوالي ساعة من المشي،
found that the trail had become flooded by recent rains,
وجدت أن الطريق أصبح مغموراً بمياه الأمطار التي هطلت مؤخراً،
so I hoisted the photo gear above my head
لذلك قمت برفع آلة التصوير فوق رأسي
as we descended into these waters up to my chest.
حيث نزلنا إلى تلك المياه حتى وصلَت إلى صدري.
After another two hours of hiking, the winding trail
وبعد ساعتين من المشي لمسافات طويلة، انتهى بنا الطريق
abruptly ended at a clearing, and before us
العاصف فجأة إلى أرض خالية من الشجر، وكان أمامنا
was a mass of holes
عدد كبير من الحُفر
that could fit into the size of a football field,
التي يمكن أن تكون بحجم ملعب كرة قدم،
and all of them were full of enslaved people laboring.
و جميعها كانت مليئة بعبيد يعملون.
Many women had children strapped to their backs
العديد من النساء يحملون أطفالاً مشدودين على ظهروهم بحزام
while they were panning for gold,
بينما كُنّ يُنقّبن عن الذهب،
wading in water poisoned by mercury.
يخوضون في ماء مسموم بالزئبق.
Mercury is used in the extraction process.
يُستخدم الزئبق في عملية الإستخراج.
These miners are enslaved in a mine shaft
عمال المناجم هؤلاء مستعبدون في مهواة منجم
in another part of Ghana.
في جزء آخر من غانا.
When they came out of the shaft, they were soaking wet
عندما خرجوا من المنجم، كانوا غارقين بالبلل
from their own sweat.
من عرَقهم.
I remember looking into their tired, bloodshot eyes,
أتذكر عندما كنت أنظر إلى أعينهم المتعبة والمحتقنة بالدم،
for many of them had been underground for 72 hours.
لأن الكثير منهم كانوا يعملون تحت الأرض لمدة 72 ساعة.
The shafts are up to 300 feet deep, and they carry out
يصل عمق المناجم إلى 300 قدم، وهم يحملون خارجاً
heavy bags of stone that later will be transported
أكياس ثقيلة من الحجر التي سيتم نقلها لاحقاً
to another area, where the stone will be pounded
إلى منطقة أخرى، حيث سيتم سحق الحجر
so that they can extract the gold.
كي يتمكنوا من استخراج الذهب.
At first glance, the pounding site seems full
يبدو موقع السحق من النظرة الأولى أنه مليء
of powerful men, but when we look closer,
بالرجال الأقوياء، لكن عندما نمعن النظر،
we see some less fortunate working on the fringes,
نرى أُناسا أسوأ حظاً يعملون على الأطراف
and children too.
و نرى أطفالا أيضاً.
All of them are victim to injury, illness and violence.
كلهم عرضة للإصابة و المرض و العنف.
In fact, it's very likely that this muscular person
في الواقع، من المحتمل جداً أن هذا الرجل قوي البنية
will end up like this one here, racked with tuberculosis
سينتهي به المطاف كهذا الرجل، مُعذّب بالسل
and mercury poisoning in just a few years.
و التسمم بالزئبق خلال سنوات قليلة.
This is Manuru. When his father died,
هذا مانورو. عندما توفي والده،
his uncle trafficked him to work with him in the mines.
تاجر به عمه ليعمل معه في المناجم.
When his uncle died, Manuru inherited his uncle's debt,
عندما توفي عمه، ورث مانورو دَين عمه،
which further forced him into being enslaved in the mines.
الذي اضطره ليكون عبداً في المناجم.
When I met him, he had been working in the mines
عندما قابلته، كان يعمل في المناجم
for 14 years, and the leg injury that you see here
لمدة 14 عاماً، وإصابة الساق التي ترونها هنا
is actually from a mining accident,
هي في الحقيقة ناتجة عن حادث مناجم،
one so severe doctors say his leg should be amputated.
وهي إصابة شديدة جداً حيث قال الأطباء أن ساقة يجب أن تُبتر.
On top of that, Manuru has tuberculosis,
و الأكثر من هذا، مانورو مصاب بالسل،
yet he's still forced to work day in and day out
ومع ذلك لا يزال يُجبر على العمل يوم بعد يوم
in that mine shaft.
في مهواة ذلك المنجم.
Even still, he has a dream that he will become free
مع هذا، لديه حلم بأن يكون حراً
and become educated with the help of local activists
و متعلماً بمساعدة ناشطين محليين
like Free the Slaves,
مثل منظمة "حرروا العبيد"،
and it's this sort of determination,
وهذا النوع من الإصرار،
in the face of unimaginable odds,
في وجه هذه العجائب التي لا يمكن تصورها،
that fills me with complete awe.
يجعلني في حالة ذهولٍ تام.
I want to shine a light on slavery.
أريد أن أسلط ضوءاً على العبودية.
When I was working in the field,
عندما كنت أعمل في الميدان،
I brought lots of candles with me,
أحضرت معي الكثير من الشموع،
and with the help of my interpreter,
و بمساعدة من المترجم الخاص بي،
I imparted to the people I was photographing
نقلت إلى الناس أني كنت ألتقط صوراً
that I wanted to illuminate their stories
لأني أردت أن أُطلع الغير على قصصهم
and their plight,
و مصيبتهم،
so when it was safe for them, and safe for me,
فعندما كان الوضع آمناً بالنسبة لهم و آمناً بالنسبة لي،
I made these images.
استطعت أن أصنع تلك الصور.
They knew their image would be seen
كانوا يعرفون أن صورهم سوف تُرى
by you out in the world.
من قبلكم في العالم الخارجي.
I wanted them to know that we will be bearing witness
أردتهم أن يعرفوا أننا سنشهد لهم
to them, and that we will do whatever we can
و أننا سنفعل ما يمكننا فعله
to help make a difference in their lives.
لنساعد في صنع فارق في حياتهم.
I truly believe, if we can see one another
أؤمن حقاً أننا لو نظرنا إلى بعضنا البعض
as fellow human beings, then it becomes very difficult
كإخوة في الإنسانية، لأصبح من الصعب
to tolerate atrocities like slavery.
التسامح مع فظائع مثل العبودية.
These images are not of issues. They are of people,
هذه الصور ليست لقضايا، بل لأُناس،
real people, like you and me, all deserving
أُناس حقيقيون، مثلي و مثلكم، جميعهم يستحقون
of the same rights, dignity and respect
أن يحظوا بنفس الحقوق والكرامة والاحترام
in their lives.
في حياتهم.
There is not a day that goes by that I don't think
لا يمر يوم دون أن أفكر
of these many beautiful, mistreated people
بهؤلاء الناس الجميلين المهانين
I've had the tremendous honor of meeting.
الذين حظيت بشرف كبير لالتقائي بهم.
I hope that these images awaken a force
آمل أن توقظ هذه الصور قوة
in those who view them, people like you,
في أولئك الذين يشاهدونها، أٌناس مثلكم،
and I hope that force will ignite a fire,
و آمل أن تُشعل هذه القوة ناراً،
and that fire will shine a light on slavery,
و تلك النار سوف تسلط الضوء على العبودية،
for without that light, the beast of bondage
لأنه من دون ذلك الضوء، سيستمر وحش العبودية
can continue to live in the shadows.
في العيش في الظل.
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
( تصفيق )